canvasjs.com 2019-06-08

# Privacy Policy - CanvasJS

We at Fenopix (Fenopix Technologies Private Limited, our subsidiaries and our affiliates) are committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy governs our data collection, processing and usage practices. It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information. By using our site, you consent to our websites privacy. 

* #### Information We Collect

##### When You Visit our Websites

You are free to explore the website without providing any personal information about yourself. When you visit the websites or download anything, we request that you provide Personal Information about yourself, and we collect Navigational Information.

##### “Personal Information”

This refers to any information that you voluntarily submit to us and that identifies you personally, including contact information, such as your name, e-mail address, company name, address, phone number, and other information about yourself or your business. Personal Information can also include information about any transactions, both free and paid, that you enter into on the website, and information about you that is available on the internet, such as from Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and Google, or publicly available information that we acquire from service providers. 

Personal Information also includes Navigational Information or Payment Information where such information can directly or indirectly identify an individual. Navigational information refers to information about your computer and your visits to this website such as your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit and pages viewed. Please see the "Navigation Information" section below. Payment information includes We collect and process payment information from you when you buy a license, including credit cards numbers and billing information, using third party PCI-compliant service providers. Except for this, we do not collect Sensitive Information from you. 

##### Log Files

When you use our services our view content provided by us, we automatically collect information about your computer hardware and software. This information can include your IP address, browser type, domain names, internet service provider (ISP), the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, clickstream data, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used by Fenopix for the operation of the Service, to maintain quality of the Service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of our websites, products or services. For these purposes, we do link this automatically-collected data to Personal Information such as name, email address, address, and phone number. 

##### Information we collect from third parties

From time to time, we may receive Personal Information about you from third party sources including partners with which we offer co-branded services or engage in joint marketing activities, and publicly available sources such as social media websites. 

* #### How We Use Information We Collect

##### Compliance with Our Privacy Policy

We use the information we collect only in compliance with this Privacy Policy. Customers who avail our products and services are obligated through our agreements with them to comply with this Privacy Policy. 

##### We Never Sell Personal Information

We will never sell your Personal Information to any third party. 

##### Use of Personal Information

In addition to the uses identified elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, we may use your Personal Information to: 

  * improve your browsing experience by personalizing the website and to improve the website, product & services; 
  * send information or relevant content to you which we think may be of interest to you by post, email, or other means and send you marketing communications relating to our business; 
  * promote use of our services to you and share promotional and information content with you in accordance with your communication preferences; 
  * provide other companies with statistical information about our users — but this information will not be used to identify any individual user; 
  * send information to you regarding changes to our Customer Terms of Service, Privacy Policy (including the Cookie Policy), EULA or other legal agreements 
  * meet legal requirements. 

We use the information collected by our customers for the following purposes: 

  * To process transactions. Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested 
  * to respond to customer support requests; and 
  * otherwise to fulfil the obligations under our End User License Agreement or other legal agreements 

##### Legal basis for processing Personal Information (EEA visitors only)

If you are a visitor/customer located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”), Fenopix Technologies Private Limited is the data controller of your personal information. Our Data Protection Officer can be contacted at [info@canvasjs.com](mailto:info@canvasjs.com)

Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. However, we will normally collect personal information from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, or where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you. 

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information). Similarly, if we collect and use your personal information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are. 

##### Use of Navigational Information

We use Navigational Information to operate and improve the website, products and service. We may also use Navigational Information alone or in combination with Personal Information to provide you with personalized information about our products and services. 

##### Customer Testimonials and Comments

We post customer testimonials and comments on our Websites, which may contain Personal Information. We obtain each customer's consent via email prior to posting the customer's name and testimonial unless it is a publicly available information like tweets and other social media posts. 

##### Use of Credit Card Information

If you give us credit card information, we use it solely to check your financial qualifications and collect payment from you. We use a third-party service provider to manage credit card processing. This service provider is not permitted to store, retain, or use information you provide except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on our behalf. 

##### Security of your Personal Information

We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. We secure the Personal Information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. All Personal Information is protected using appropriate physical, technical and organizational measures. 

##### Social Media Features

Our Website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our sites. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our sites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Websites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to these features. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy and other policies of the companies providing them. 

##### External Websites

Our Website provides links to other websites. We do not control, and are not responsible for, the content or practices of these other websites. Our provision of such links does not constitute our endorsement of these other websites, their content, their owners, or their practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to these other websites, which are subject to any privacy and other policies they may have. 

##### Public Forums

We offer publicly accessible message boards, blogs, and community forums. Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose any information through our public message boards, blogs, or forums, this information may be collected and used by others. We will correct or delete any information you have posted on the Websites if you so request, as described in "Opting Out and Unsubscribing" below. 

##### Retention of Personal Information

How long we keep information we collect about you depends on the type of information. as described in further detail below. After such time, we will either delete or anonymize your information or, if this is not possible, then we will securely store your information and isolate it from any further use until deletion is possible. 

We retain Personal Information that you provide to us where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, as long as is required in order to contact you about the product or service, or as needed to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements). 

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your Personal Information, we securely delete the information or anonymise it or, if this is not possible, then we will securely store your Personal Information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible. We will delete this information from the servers at an earlier date if you so request, as described in “To Unsubscribe from Our Communications” below. 

If you have elected to receive marketing communications from us, we retain information about your marketing preferences for a reasonable period of time from the date you last expressed interest in our content, products, or services, such as when you last opened an email from us or ceased using your account. We retain information derived from cookies and other tracking technologies for a reasonable period of time from the date such information was created. 

* #### How we Share Information we Collect

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. 

##### Service Providers

We employ other companies and people to provide services to visitors to our Websites, our customers, and users of the Product and may need to share your information with them to provide information, products or services to you. Examples may include removing repetitive information from prospect lists, analyzing data or performing statistical analysis, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, supplementing the information you provide us in order to provide you with better service, and providing customer service or support. In all cases where we share your information with such agents, we explicitly require the agent to acknowledge and adhere to our privacy and customer data handling policies. 

##### Fenopix Partners

In addition, we may share data with trusted partners to contact you based on your request to receive such communications, help us perform statistical analysis, or provide customer support. Such third parties are prohibited from using your Personal Information except for these purposes, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information. 

We partner with trusted third parties to provide you with co-marketing content that we think may be relevant to you. When you engage with these co-marketing partners, we will tell you who we are sharing data with, and provide a link to the co-marketing partner’s privacy policy so you can learn more about how to opt-out of the partner’s communications. 

##### Corporate Events

If we (or our assets) are acquired by another company, whether by merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or otherwise, that company would receive all information gathered by Fenopix on the Website. In this event, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership, uses of your Personal Information, and choices you may have regarding your Personal Information. 

##### Compelled Disclosure

We reserve the right to use or disclose your Personal Information if required by law or if we reasonably believe that use or disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or comply with a law, court order, or legal process. 

* #### International Transfer of Information

Some or all of your data may be stored or transferred outside of the European Economic Area (“the EEA”) (The EEA consists of all EU member states, plus Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein). You are deemed to accept and agree to this by using Our Site and submitting information to Us. If we do store or transfer data outside the EEA, we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated as safely and securely as it would be within the EEA and under the GDPR. 

##### International Transfer to third parties

Some of the third parties which provide services to us under contract, are based in other countries that may not have equivalent privacy and data protection laws to the country in which you reside. 

* #### Cookies and Similar Technologies

##### Cookies

Fenopix and its partners use cookies or similar technologies (such as web beacons) to analyze trends, administer the website, track users movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. To find out more about how we use cookies on our website and how to manage your cookie preferences please see our Cookie Policy. 

##### Advertising

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking here: <http://preferences.truste.com/> (or if located in the European Union, by clicking here: <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

##### Third Party Tracking Technologies

The use of cookies and web beacons by any tracking utility company is not covered by our Privacy Policy or Cookie Policy. 

* #### How to Access & Control Your Personal Data

##### Reviewing, Correcting and Removing Your Personal Information

You have the following data protection rights: 

  * You can request access, correction, updates or deletion of your personal information. 
  * You can object to processing of your personal information, ask us to restrict processing of your personal information or request portability of your personal information. If we have collected and process your personal information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent. 

To exercise any of these rights, please contact us at [info@canvasjs.com](mailto:info@canvasjs.com). We will respond to your request to change, correct, or delete your information within a reasonable timeframe and notify you of the action we have taken. 

##### To Unsubscribe From Our Communications

You may unsubscribe from our marketing communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of our e-mails, updating your communication preferences, or by sending us email at [sales@canvasjs.com](mailto:sales@canvasjs.com). Customers cannot opt out of receiving transactional emails related to their account with us, license or the update subscription. 

* #### Changes to our Privacy Policy

We periodically update this Privacy Policy. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page. All amended terms will be automatically effective without further notice, 10 days after they are first posted. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically.
